The end begins
Left Behind is a thriller, action, science fiction
film directed by Vic Armstrong.
A small group of survivors are left behind after millions of people suddenly vanish
during the rapture and the world is plunged into chaos and destruction.
Rayford Steele, played by Nicolas Cage.
Buck Williams, played by Chad Michael Murray.
Irene Steele, played by Lea Thompson.
Hattie Durham, played by Nicky Whelan.
Melvin Weir, played by Martin Klebba.
Simon, played by Quinton Aaron.
Left Behind is a 2014 American Christian apocalyptic thriller film directed
by Vic Armstrong and written by Paul LaLonde and John Patus.
Based on the 1995 novel of the same name written by Tim LaHaye and Jerry B.
Jenkins, the film stars Nicolas Cage, Chad Michael Murray, Cassi
Thomson, Nicky Whelan, Jordin Sparks, and Lea Thompson.
It is the second film adaptation of the first novel in the Left Behind series.
It depicts the worldwide disaster of the Christian Rapture from the perspective of one family: a husband
(airline pilot Rayford Steele) and wife facing marital difficulties, as well as their two children.
The plot was altered to mostly take place on an
airplane and the Antichrist does not appear.
Left Behind was released in theaters on October 3, 2014, by Freestyle Releasing.
It was panned by critics and grossed $27.4 million worldwide
against its $16 million production budget.
A sequel featuring a new cast, titled Left Behind: Rise
of the Antichrist, was released in 2023.
The film explores themes of airplane, the rapture, remake, disaster, pilot hero.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.